PRATEEK PATEL

Software Developer Engineer

prateekmedy@gmail.com

+91 8871697651



in linkedin.com/in/prateekmedy







Enthusiastic Software Developer with competencies in Web Development. Offers 2+ years of software development expertise. Skilled in directing development with a creative and performance-oriented approach. Well-organized and customer-focused with proven skills in project management and teamwork.

WORK HISTORY

Software Developer Engineer

Calsoft Inc., Pune | 08/2019 - Present

Works as a front-end web developer and be a part of technical & UI/UX components designing for the application. Also responsible to solve the customer's issues in their production environment.

- Awarded as Rising Star for outstanding performance.
- Praised by Product Designer for evaluating and improve User Interface and UX Designs of application. 0
- Improved and optimized the performance up to 30% from the older version of the application. 0
- Quickly & Efficiently Resolved customer's problems by providing them effective solutions. 0
- Redesign & Create, new logic to modularize the application and makes it 25% more debug friendly. 0
- Wrote highly maintainable and solid code that reduces the bug count by 40% in the application. 0

Software Developer Intern

Calsoft Inc., Pune | 01/2019 - 07/2019

Introduced to the web development in the cloud platform as a ServiceNow development and follow the agile methodology to develop and maintain quality applications.

- Followed the Agile Scrum methodologies and effective development. 0
- Followed best practices to enhance product development and task tracking. 0
- Designed and Developed challenging intuitive application components. 0

Junior Web Developer Intern

Webdunia-Diaspark, Indore | 07/2018 - 08/2018

Assisted with design and development of CMS for Yoga & Karma projects as an Intern at Webdunia, Diaspark Infotech Pvt. Ltd., Indore.

PROJECTS

VMware vRealize Automation ITSM Application.

Calsoft Inc.

This is the official project, currently working with Calsoft Inc. And it's a ServiceNow Plugin Application for Integration with VMware VRealize Automation (vRA). The vRA plugin for ServiceNow provides an OOB integration between the ServiceNow portal and vRA Catalog and governance model.

Application link at ServiceNow Store:- Click Here

ServiceNow

JavaScript

JIRA

SKILLS & TOOLS

Technical

JavaScript

React.js/Redux

Firebase/MongoDB/MySQL

UI/UX & Responsive Designing

Blockchain

ServiceNow

Professional

Effective Communication

Team Player

Strong Problem Solver

Creative Thinker

Others

HTML/CSS/SASS IPFS PWA

JIRA Github AdobeXD

3D Modeling Asana

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (IT)

Indore Institute of Science and Technology, Indore

2015 - 2019

8.12 CGPA Star Achiever

High School (PCM)

CBSE. Indore 2014 - 2015

Best Student of the Year

DigiVote - Blockchain DApp (Major Project)

Personal Project

"DigiVote" - Digital Voting powered by Blockchain. This Project is the Implementation of how Blockchain Technology uses for Our Indian Election Voting System. Through Blockchain we can assure Vote security and transparency in the Elections.

Project Story Video:- https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WLwfCgLHK5Y

Project Github Link:- https://github.com/Prateekmedy/DigiVote

Ethereum Blockchain

ReactJS

Web3JS

IPFS

Portfolio 2.0 - CMS

Personal Project

This is a personal Portfolio Project. It's a Content Management System for personal Portfolio 2.0 (https://prateekmedy.github.io/prateekportfolio). This web application is created to manage (Create, Read, Update & Delete) the data associate with my Portfolio.

Project Link:- https://portfolio2-5ed4d.web.app/

Project Github Link:- https://github.com/Prateekmedy/Portfolio2.0_Backend

Firebase-CloudStore

ReactJS





ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Awarded by "Rising Star" at Calsoft Inc. in 2021

4-Star Badge on Problem Solving, HackerRank

React JS Certificate, HackerRank

Front End Development Certificate, Free Code Camp.

JavaScript Algorithm and Data Structures Certificate, Free Code Camp.

Head of Operations of Entrepreneur Cell of College.

LANGUAGES

English (Professional)

Hindi (Native)

INTERESTS

Sketching

Doodling

Playing Musical Instruments